<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MapLibre</title><link>https://maplibre.org/</link><description>Recent content on MapLibre</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC0</copyright><atom:link href="https://maplibre.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MapLibre GL JS</title><link>https://maplibre.org/projects/maplibre-gl-js/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/projects/maplibre-gl-js/</guid><description>Open-source TypeScript library for publishing maps on your website. Fast displaying of maps is possible thanks to GPU-accelerated vector tile rendering.
MapLibre GL JS originated as an open-source fork of mapbox-gl-js and MapLibre GL JS v1 is fully compatible with Mapbox GL JS v1.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Native</title><link>https://maplibre.org/projects/maplibre-native/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/projects/maplibre-native/</guid><description>Open-source SDK for Android and iOS allowing displaying maps inside of your mobile applications, desktop application, or embedded devices. This toolset grants fast maps displaying in iOS and Android apps using the same GPU-based acceleration as the TypeScript version.</description></item><item><title>Charter</title><link>https://maplibre.org/charter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/charter/</guid><description>MapLibre Charter Definitions MapLibre Organization: An umbrella organization to develop, maintain and promote MapLibre software projects.
MapLibre Projects: Multiple repositories, each being some part of the map visualization stack from the raw data to the map visualization and interaction.</description></item><item><title>Jobs</title><link>https://maplibre.org/jobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/jobs/</guid><description>Jobs Working for MapLibre means that everything you do is going to be open-source, you will have a huge impact on the entire geospatial industry as our libraries are used everywhere, you will interact with a global community of nice people who contribute to the projects, you will work with world-class engineers from AWS and Meta, and you will be able to build a professional network in the mapping world.</description></item><item><title>Sponsors</title><link>https://maplibre.org/sponsors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/sponsors/</guid><description>Sponsors The MapLibre Organization is community-governed, and we are thankful for all contributions no matter how small or large they are. The following companies decided to join the MapLibre Sponsorship Program and support us financially to ensure that the MapLibre Organization has a healthy and sustainable future where we can build mapping software together in a friendly and welcoming community.</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs</title><link>https://maplibre.org/projects/maplibre-rs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/projects/maplibre-rs/</guid><description>maplibre-rs, an experimental project, is a portable and performant vector maps renderer. We aim to support web, mobile and desktop applications. This is achieved by the novel WebGPU specification. Plenty of native implementations are already implementing this specification.</description></item><item><title>Martin</title><link>https://maplibre.org/projects/martin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/projects/martin/</guid><description>Martin is a tile server able to generate vector tiles from large PostGIS databases on the fly, or serve tiles from PMTile and MBTile files. Martin optimizes for speed and heavy traffic, and is written in Rust .</description></item><item><title>Additional Projects</title><link>https://maplibre.org/projects/additional-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/projects/additional-projects/</guid><description>Binding for additional languages (such as React.js, Vue, Flutter) and external libraries.
awesome-maplibre on GitHub All MapLibre GitHub repositories</description></item><item><title>Community</title><link>https://maplibre.org/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/community/</guid><description>Community Welcome to Our Community The people in our community talk with each other mainly in the following three ways: Discussions, Issues, and Pull Requests on GitHub You find all Discussions, Issues, and Pull Requests in our public GitHub repostories.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Newsletter June 2023</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-23-maplibre-newsletter-june-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-23-maplibre-newsletter-june-2023/</guid><description>MapLibre Newsletter - June 2023 Highlights JawgMaps We would like to thank JawgMaps for their trust. As you might have read in our previous announcement , JawgMaps has joined the MapLibre Sponsorship Program and supports us as a Silver Sponsor!</description></item><item><title>JawgMaps becomes a MapLibre Silver Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-22-jawgmaps-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-22-jawgmaps-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</guid><description>We are happy to announce that JawgMaps has joined the MapLibre Sponsorship Program and supports us as a Silver Sponsor!
The JawgMaps platform provides enterprise-grade mapping services built from both OpenSource and proprietary tools, as well as OpenStreetMap data.</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs monthly (special issue)</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-07-maplibre-rs-monthly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:46:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-07-maplibre-rs-monthly/</guid><description>It is finally time for a new maplibre-rs monthly! Or should I say yearly? The last update was 2022 and we already have 2023! The development of maplibre-rs did not come to a total standstill, even though it may look like it did.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre GL JS v3</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-05-23-maplibre-gl-js-v3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-05-23-maplibre-gl-js-v3/</guid><description>This release is a big step for MapLibre GL JS! With more than 500 commits, and almost a year in the making, version 3.0.0 is surely our best release yet.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Newsletter May 2023</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-05-18-maplibre-newsletter-may-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-05-18-maplibre-newsletter-may-2023/</guid><description>MapLibre Newsletter - May 2023 Highlights Mierune We would like to thank our first sponsor Mierune for their continued trust in MapLibre.
MapLibre Innovation Lab Many real-world applications have been built with MapLibre.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Newsletter April 2023</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-04-14-maplibre-newsletter-april-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-04-14-maplibre-newsletter-april-2023/</guid><description>MapLibre Newsletter - April 2023 Highlights Komoot joined the MapLibre Sponsorship Program as a Silver Sponsor. Welcome komoot, we are glad to have you in the MapLibre community! Read the news announcement&amp;hellip; We released version 2.</description></item><item><title>Komoot becomes a MapLibre Silver Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-04-06-komoot-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-04-06-komoot-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</guid><description>We are happy to announce that komoot has joined the MapLibre Sponsorship Program and supports us as a Silver Sponsor!
Komoot is an app that lets you find, plan, and share adventures with its easy route planner.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Navigation Android V2.0.0 Released</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-27-android-navigation-version-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-27-android-navigation-version-2/</guid><description>We just released version 2.0.0 of MapLibre&amp;rsquo;s navigation library . The update comes with the latest version of MapLibre Native (10.0.2) and includes a navigation UI by default.
MapLibre Navigation Android is an open source navigation library which allows everyone to build a customized navigation experience on Android.</description></item><item><title>Metal Project Team Started</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-23-metal-project-team-started/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-23-metal-project-team-started/</guid><description>The Metal project team has started working! The goal is to deliver a Metal beta release for MapLibre Native by the end of 2023.
AWS and Meta are teaming up in this effort because they both recognize the importance of Metal as a modern graphics backend on Apple devices.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Newsletter March 2023</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-20-maplibre-newsletter-march-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-20-maplibre-newsletter-march-2023/</guid><description>MapLibre Newsletter - March 2023 General Bounty Program We invite you to share feedback on what features and improvements in MapLibre GL JS and MapLibre Native would be helpful for you.</description></item><item><title>Second Call for Bounties</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-13-second-call-for-bounties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-13-second-call-for-bounties/</guid><description>We are happy to invite you to a second round of voting on Bounty directions. Please let us know which features would be helpful for you and upvote existing suggestions.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Newsletter February 2023</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-02-16-maplibre-newsletter-february-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-02-16-maplibre-newsletter-february-2023/</guid><description>MapLibre Newsletter - February 2023 General We have successfully registered the MapLibre trademark in the US and in the EU . Open Source Collective, our fiscal host, holds the MapLibre trademarks.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre React Native Announcement</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-02-08-maplibre-react-native-announcement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-02-08-maplibre-react-native-announcement/</guid><description>MapLibre has completed onboarding of MapLibre React Native , an SDK that will make MapLibre Native more accessible to mobile developers.
The project is a fork of rnmapbox , a community-maintained React Native library for building maps with the Mapbox iOS and Android SDKs.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre User Group Japan</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-23-maplibre-user-group-japan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-23-maplibre-user-group-japan/</guid><description>If you speak Japanese and you are interested in map rendering, have a look at the newly created MapLibre User Group Japan.
Official Website: https://bit.ly/mug--jp Twitter Space: https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1OyKAVvlgvbGb Yasunori Kirimoto and Kanahiro Iguchi who are both MapLibre Voting Members are organizing the User Group.</description></item><item><title>Bounty Directions</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-20-bounty-directions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-20-bounty-directions/</guid><description>The MapLibre Bounty Program will support the following cross-project directions: Terrain3D, globe view, documentation, performance, Brahmic/Indic scripts, MapLibre Innovation Lab.
We invited the broader community to give feedback and share ideas for cross-project directions in a discussion group on GitHub .</description></item><item><title>Harel Mazor starts as Maintainer Web</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-harel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-harel/</guid><description>We are happy to share that we were able to contract Harel Mazor, the long-time lead-maintainer of MapLibre GL JS, for the Maintainer Web role. Please give him a warm welcome!</description></item><item><title>Ovidiu Voda starts as Maintainer Native</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-ovi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-ovi/</guid><description>With Ovidiu Voda starting today, we are proud to now have two people working as Maintainers on MapLibre Native. Please give Ovi a warm welcome!
Ovi is going to work together with Bart Louwers on Native and he is looking forward to meeting everyone involved in the project.</description></item><item><title>Grab Talk Khmer</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-12-grab-talk-khmer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-12-grab-talk-khmer/</guid><description>Alan Wei Chen from GrabMaps is giving a talk about how Grab renders text labels in the Khmer language using FreeType and HarfBuzz in the next MapLibre Eastern Call. Feel free to join the presentation!</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes January</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-11-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-11-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>We had our first monthly meeting of 2023. You find the meeting notes here: #187 Feel free to join our next monthly meeting on Wednesday, Feb 8th, 2023. The technical steering committee meetings are open to everyone!</description></item><item><title>Developing Plugins for MapLibre Interoperability</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-03-aws-maplibre-plugins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-03-aws-maplibre-plugins/</guid><description>Considering that MapLibre is an open-source fork of the Mapbox rendering library, many of the Mapbox plugins can be used in conjunction with MapLibre without any issue in JavaScript. However, since MapLibre is a TypeScript library in the same spirit, if you wish to use some of the popular Mapbox plugins in your TypeScript application you will likely run into the TypeScript compiler throwing a lot of type inference errors.</description></item><item><title>Bart Louwers starts as Maintainer Native</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-03-announcement-bart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-03-announcement-bart/</guid><description>Today, Bart Louwers is starting to work with MapLibre in the Maintainer Native role. Let&amp;rsquo;s give him a warm welcome!
Bart is excited to meet the people involved in the project and learn more about the codebase and the community behind it.</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs monthly</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-12-18-maplibre-rs-monthly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-12-18-maplibre-rs-monthly/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an upcoming and cross-platform vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers, visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or join the MapLibre (#maplibre and #maplibre-rs) community within the OpenStreetMap Slack.</description></item><item><title>Call for Bounties💰</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-16-call-for-bounties/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-16-call-for-bounties/</guid><description>If you have ideas for new features which you would love to see from MapLibre, you can now share your idea and tell us that we should allocate Bounties for it.</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes December</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-12-15-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-12-15-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Yesterday, we had a first MapLibre Eastern Call at 9 AM CET, the native technical steering committee meeting at 7 PM CET, and the web technical steering committee meeting at 8 PM CET.</description></item><item><title>Metal Announcement</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-28-metal-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-28-metal-announcement/</guid><description>MapLibre Native is planning for modularization and migration to Metal, Apple&amp;rsquo;s graphics framework, for rendering on iOS mobile devices.
A design proposal for the modularization of the map rendering architecture can be found at #547 .</description></item><item><title>Work on Open-Source</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-11-work-on-open-source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-11-work-on-open-source/</guid><description>We thank all our sponsors for their generous financial support and assistance in building the MapLibre Organization.
We were successful in securing initial funding and would now like to pay people from the community for coordination, maintenance, and development work.</description></item><item><title>Oliver Wipfli becomes MapLibre's first Coordinator</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-07-oliver-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-07-oliver-coordinator/</guid><description>The MapLibre Governing Board selected Oliver Wipfli to work as Coordinator of the MapLibre Organization. Oliver did this very well until now in his free time, and we need immediate action.</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs monthly</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-09-24-maplibre-rs-monthly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-09-24-maplibre-rs-monthly/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an upcoming and cross-platform vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers, visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or join the MapLibre (#maplibre and #maplibre-rs) community within the OpenStreetMap Slack.</description></item><item><title>Governing Board Election and Charter Approval</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-09-02-election/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-09-02-election/</guid><description>On Thursday, Aug 25th, 2022, the MapLibre Voting Members elected for the first time a Governing Board and they approved the MapLibre Charter. We thank all the candidates and Voting Members for participating in this process!</description></item><item><title>Meta becomes a MapLibre Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-26-meta-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-26-meta-announcement/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce that Meta now is a sponsor of the MapLibre Organization. Thanks for your generous help and for all the trust you put in us!
Meta has been involved in the MapLibre Organization since the very beginning, helped setting up the initial fork, and provided guidance on non-trivial questions around licensing.</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs paper published</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-24-maplibre-rs-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-24-maplibre-rs-paper/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an experimental &amp;amp; portable vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers, visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or our Slack at osmus.</description></item><item><title>AWS becomes a MapLibre Platinum Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-22-aws-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-22-aws-announcement/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce the Amazon Web Services (AWS) support for the MapLibre Organization as a Platinum Sponsor. Thanks for your generous support and for all the trust you put in us!</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes May</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-07-13-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-07-13-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #69 .</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs monthly</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-26-maplibre-rs-monthly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-26-maplibre-rs-monthly/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an upcoming and cross-platform vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or join the MapLibre (#maplibre and #maplibre-rs) community within the OpenStreetMap Slack.</description></item><item><title>MIERUNE Inc. supports MapLibre with USD 10'000</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-10-mierune-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-10-mierune-announcement/</guid><description>Recently, MIERUNE Inc. from Japan decided to support MapLibre financially with a generous donation of USD 10'000, see https://opencollective.com/maplibre . This is the largest ammount that MapLibre has received to date.</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes June</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-08-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-08-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #34 .</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs monthly</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-23-maplibre-rs-monthly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:16:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-23-maplibre-rs-monthly/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an upcoming and cross-platform vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or join the MapLibre (#maplibre and #maplibre-rs) community within the OpenStreetMap Slack.</description></item><item><title>Terrain3D</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-20-terrain3d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-20-terrain3d/</guid><description>The Terrain3D #1022 of Max Demmelbauer from Toursprung was merged into main. Thanks for all the hard work!
You can now try out the 3D feature yourself with the pre-release version MapLibre GL JS v2.</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs weekly</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-13-maplibre-rs-weekly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-13-maplibre-rs-weekly/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an upcoming and cross-platform vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or join the MapLibre (#maplibre and #maplibre-rs) community within the OpenStreetMap Slack.</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes May</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-11-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-11-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #28 . Terrain3D can be merged now :) Thanks Max and everyone at Toursprung for their contributions!</description></item><item><title>maplibre-rs weekly</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-06-maplibre-rs-weekly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-05-06-maplibre-rs-weekly/</guid><description>maplibre-rs is an upcoming and cross-platform vector map renderer written in Rust. If you want to get in touch with the developers visit the #maplibre:matrix.org chat or our Slack at osmus.</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes April</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-04-06-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-04-06-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #15 . Terrain 3D might be a matter of days or weeks only until we can merge and make a pre-release.</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes March</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-03-09-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-03-09-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #14 .</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes February</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-02-09-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-02-09-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #9 . Terrain 3D is coming soon. Thanks Max and everyone at Toursprung for contributing this new feature!</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes November</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2021-11-10-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2021-11-10-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #3 .</description></item><item><title>Steering Committee Notes October</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2021-10-13-steering-committee-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2021-10-13-steering-committee-notes/</guid><description>Steering committee meeting notes available #2 .</description></item></channel></rss>