<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>announcements on MapLibre</title><link>https://maplibre.org/categories/announcements/</link><description>Recent content in announcements on MapLibre</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maplibre.org/categories/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New People Joining the Maplibre Team</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-10-04-new-team-members/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-10-04-new-team-members/</guid><description>Three new people have joined the MapLibre Team. Please give them a warm welcome!
Isaac Besora has joined MapLibre as Graphics Engineer. His initial focus will be improvements in MapLibre GL JS in particular in the areas of Terrain 3D and the new Globe feature.</description></item><item><title>Governing Board Election 2024</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-08-30-governing-board-election-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-08-30-governing-board-election-2024/</guid><description>The MapLibre Governing Board members serve for a one year term and at the end of August we hold the Board election with representatives of the community, the MapLibre Voting Members.</description></item><item><title>Mapme joins the MapLibre Sponsorship Program</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-06-28-mapme-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-06-28-mapme-announcement/</guid><description>Mapme joins the MapLibre Sponsorship Program as a Silver Sponsor.
The Silver tier donation of USD 10,000 will be used for general maintenance of the MapLibre codebases and project coordination.</description></item><item><title>Mappedin joins the MapLibre Sponsorship Program</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-03-26-mappedin-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-03-26-mappedin-announcement/</guid><description>Mappedin joins the MapLibre Sponsorship Program at the Silver tier.
With a yearly donation of USD $10,000, Mappedin supports the maintenance of MapLibre’s codebases and ensures a stable future for the project.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft joins the MapLibre Sponsorship Program</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-02-20-msft-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-02-20-msft-announcement/</guid><description>Microsoft joins the MapLibre Sponsorship Program as a Silver Sponsor.
The Silver tier donation of USD 80,000 will be used to 20 percent for development of new features and to 80 percent for general maintenance of the MapLibre codebases and project coordination.</description></item><item><title>Metal Support for MapLibre Native iOS Is Here!</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-01-19-metal-support-for-maplibre-native-ios-is-here/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2024-01-19-metal-support-for-maplibre-native-ios-is-here/</guid><description>We are excited to announce the release of MapLibre Native for iOS v6.0.0 with Metal support!
MapLibre Native is a map rendering toolkit written in C++ that can be used on many different platforms.</description></item><item><title>Meta continues to support MapLibre</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-11-08-meta-continues-to-support-maplibre/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-11-08-meta-continues-to-support-maplibre/</guid><description>Meta continues to support MapLibre and increases its donation from the Silver to the Gold tier in its second year of sponsorship.
The Gold tier donation of USD 150,000 will be used to 25 percent for development of new features and to 75 percent for general maintenance of the MapLibre codebases and project coordination.</description></item><item><title>Results of the 2023 MapLibre Governing Board Election</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-08-30-results-governing-board-election/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-08-30-results-governing-board-election/</guid><description>The MapLibre Governing Board Elections are finished - all existing Board members have been reelected.
MapLibre Governing Board 2023 Birk Skyum Harel Mazor Luke Seelenbinder Petr Pridal Yuri Astrakhan Congratulations to the elected Board members and a big thank you to Jonah Adkins for running for the Board as the only newcomer!</description></item><item><title>Radar becomes a MapLibre Silver Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-08-11-radar-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-08-11-radar-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</guid><description>Radar is joining the MapLibre Sponsorship Program as a Silver Sponsor.
Tim Julien, CTO at Radar, was so kind to share a few insights into Radar and its relationship to MapLibre below:</description></item><item><title>Governing Board Elections 2023</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-08-02-governing-board-elections-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-08-02-governing-board-elections-2023/</guid><description>Governing Board Elections 2023 The Governing Board Elections 2023 will take place August 24th, 2023. We want to emphasize the process of nominating Candidates for the Governing Board as well as new Voting Members and are looking forward to your suggestions.</description></item><item><title>JawgMaps becomes a MapLibre Silver Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-22-jawgmaps-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-06-22-jawgmaps-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</guid><description>We are happy to announce that JawgMaps has joined the MapLibre Sponsorship Program and supports us as a Silver Sponsor!
The JawgMaps platform provides enterprise-grade mapping services built from both OpenSource and proprietary tools, as well as OpenStreetMap data.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre GL JS v3</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-05-23-maplibre-gl-js-v3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-05-23-maplibre-gl-js-v3/</guid><description>This release is a big step for MapLibre GL JS! With more than 500 commits, and almost a year in the making, version 3.0.0 is surely our best release yet.</description></item><item><title>Komoot becomes a MapLibre Silver Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-04-06-komoot-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-04-06-komoot-becomes-a-maplibre-silver-sponsor/</guid><description>We are happy to announce that komoot has joined the MapLibre Sponsorship Program and supports us as a Silver Sponsor!
Komoot is an app that lets you find, plan, and share adventures with its easy route planner.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre Navigation Android V2.0.0 Released</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-27-android-navigation-version-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-27-android-navigation-version-2/</guid><description>We just released version 2.0.0 of MapLibre&amp;rsquo;s navigation library. The update comes with the latest version of MapLibre Native (10.0.2) and includes a navigation UI by default.
MapLibre Navigation Android is an open source navigation library which allows everyone to build a customized navigation experience on Android.</description></item><item><title>Metal Project Team Started</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-23-metal-project-team-started/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-23-metal-project-team-started/</guid><description>The Metal project team has started working! The goal is to deliver a Metal beta release for MapLibre Native by the end of 2023.
AWS and Meta are teaming up in this effort because they both recognize the importance of Metal as a modern graphics backend on Apple devices.</description></item><item><title>Second Call for Bounties</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-13-second-call-for-bounties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-03-13-second-call-for-bounties/</guid><description>We are happy to invite you to a second round of voting on Bounty directions. Please let us know which features would be helpful for you and upvote existing suggestions.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre React Native Announcement</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-02-08-maplibre-react-native-announcement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-02-08-maplibre-react-native-announcement/</guid><description>MapLibre has completed onboarding of MapLibre React Native, an SDK that will make MapLibre Native more accessible to mobile developers.
The project is a fork of rnmapbox, a community-maintained React Native library for building maps with the Mapbox iOS and Android SDKs.</description></item><item><title>MapLibre User Group Japan</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-23-maplibre-user-group-japan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-23-maplibre-user-group-japan/</guid><description>If you speak Japanese and you are interested in map rendering, have a look at the newly created MapLibre User Group Japan.
Official Website X Space Yasunori Kirimoto and Kanahiro Iguchi who are both MapLibre Voting Members are organizing the User Group.</description></item><item><title>Bounty Directions</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-20-bounty-directions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-20-bounty-directions/</guid><description>The MapLibre Bounty Program will support the following cross-project directions: Terrain3D, globe view, documentation, performance, Brahmic/Indic scripts, MapLibre Innovation Lab.
We invited the broader community to give feedback and share ideas for cross-project directions in a discussion group on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Harel Mazor starts as Maintainer Web</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-harel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-harel/</guid><description>We are happy to share that we were able to contract Harel Mazor, the long-time lead-maintainer of MapLibre GL JS, for the Maintainer Web role. Please give him a warm welcome!</description></item><item><title>Ovidiu Voda starts as Maintainer Native</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-ovi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-16-announcement-ovi/</guid><description>With Ovidiu Voda starting today, we are proud to now have two people working as Maintainers on MapLibre Native. Please give Ovi a warm welcome!
Ovi is going to work together with Bart Louwers on Native and he is looking forward to meeting everyone involved in the project.</description></item><item><title>Grab Talk Khmer</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-12-grab-talk-khmer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-12-grab-talk-khmer/</guid><description>Alan Wei Chen from GrabMaps is giving a talk about how Grab renders text labels in the Khmer language using FreeType and HarfBuzz in the next MapLibre Eastern Call. Feel free to join the presentation!</description></item><item><title>Bart Louwers starts as Maintainer Native</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-03-announcement-bart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2023-01-03-announcement-bart/</guid><description>Today, Bart Louwers is starting to work with MapLibre in the Maintainer Native role. Let&amp;rsquo;s give him a warm welcome!
Bart is excited to meet the people involved in the project and learn more about the codebase and the community behind it.</description></item><item><title>Call for Bounties💰</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-16-call-for-bounties/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-16-call-for-bounties/</guid><description>If you have ideas for new features which you would love to see from MapLibre, you can now share your idea and tell us that we should allocate Bounties for it.</description></item><item><title>Work on Open-Source</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-11-work-on-open-source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-11-work-on-open-source/</guid><description>We thank all our sponsors for their generous financial support and assistance in building the MapLibre Organization.
We were successful in securing initial funding and would now like to pay people from the community for coordination, maintenance, and development work.</description></item><item><title>Oliver Wipfli becomes MapLibre's first Coordinator</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-07-oliver-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-10-07-oliver-coordinator/</guid><description>The MapLibre Governing Board selected Oliver Wipfli to work as Coordinator of the MapLibre Organization. Oliver did this very well until now in his free time, and we need immediate action.</description></item><item><title>Governing Board Election and Charter Approval</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-09-02-election/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-09-02-election/</guid><description>On Thursday, Aug 25th, 2022, the MapLibre Voting Members elected for the first time a Governing Board and they approved the MapLibre Charter. We thank all the candidates and Voting Members for participating in this process!</description></item><item><title>Meta becomes a MapLibre Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-26-meta-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-26-meta-announcement/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce that Meta now is a sponsor of the MapLibre Organization. Thanks for your generous help and for all the trust you put in us!
Meta has been involved in the MapLibre Organization since the very beginning, helped setting up the initial fork, and provided guidance on non-trivial questions around licensing.</description></item><item><title>AWS becomes a MapLibre Platinum Sponsor</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-22-aws-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-08-22-aws-announcement/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce the Amazon Web Services (AWS) support for the MapLibre Organization as a Platinum Sponsor. Thanks for your generous support and for all the trust you put in us!</description></item><item><title>MIERUNE Inc. supports MapLibre with USD 10'000</title><link>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-10-mierune-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2022-06-10-mierune-announcement/</guid><description>Recently, MIERUNE Inc. from Japan decided to support MapLibre financially with a generous donation of USD 10'000, see https://opencollective.com/maplibre. This is the largest ammount that MapLibre has received to date.</description></item></channel></rss>